Tom Sanderson

Software Developer

Address Ajax, Ontario, L1Z 0A2

Phone 416 878 8929

E-mail tom.w.j.sanderson@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/tom-sanderson-b6bb5084

Website https://tomsanderson.ca/

Passionate Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience using React, Redux, Express & PostgreSQL. Analytical and precise professional with 2.5+ years of hands-on experience taking charge of front and back-end web development. DevOps experience with Firebase, Google Cloud Services Platform & Heroku. Skillful at creating servers and databases for precise functionality and designing resilient APIs. Hardworking collaborator with track record of superior results.

Skills

React/Redux
HTML & CSS
Node.js (Express)
Firebase/Firestore
PostgreSQL
JavaScript
Interpersonal Communication

Work History

2021-06 - Current

Web Development Mentor (Part-Time)

Lighthouse Labs, Toronto, Ontario

- Assist and guide students through web development bootcamp curriculum
- Help students to understand technical concepts and work through blockers
- Support and encourage students as they progress through the bootcamp and its many challenges

2021-05 - 2021-07

Full Stack Web Developer (Contract)

Glowinme, Toronto, Ontario

- Collaborated with Founders to establish project goals, projections and milestones.
- Designed and developed efficient and maintainable software using React/Redux & Firebase according to business objectives.
- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.

• Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.

2020-06 - Current

QA Engineer/Support Specialist

Hifyre, Hamilton, Ontario

- Developed and executed QA test cases, scripts and procedures for automated software maintenance.
- Resolved technical issues and forecasted troubleshooting complications during software trials.
- Designed, executed and maintained automated test scripts for in-project deployment.
- Collaborated with Product Managers to establish, meet and maintain quality assurance thresholds based on best-practice tools.

2019-10 - 2020-05

Web Developer

Freelance, Toronto, Ontario

- Built custom made websites and applications for start ups and small businesses
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design.

2019-05 - 2019-09

Junior Web Developer

ZendulT, Mississauga, ON

- Built a back-end API integration from scratch using Node.js & Typescript
- Architected and implemented the API integration between the Geotab API and client IoT products
- Responsible for weekly project updates with clients, project manager & stakeholders
- Wrote unit tests for various MEAN stack applications
- Collaborated with other junior developers to solve problems and engage in knowledge sharing

Education

2018-11 - 2019-02 Bootcamp: Web Development

Lighthouse Labs - Toronto, ON

2008-09 - 2010-04 Bachelor of Arts: History & Philosophy

University of Guelph - Guelph, ON